Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Mount Vernon Seminary and College graphics, publications, and administrative material collection, 1890-2000 MVC0035.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Photographs, 1875-2002; 1880-1999; Series 2
  - Oversized Photos, 1900-1997; 1978-1997; Series 2 Subseries 8
    - Campus Buildings, Undated; Series 2 Subseries 8 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Faculty member in his office, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Fairfay, Lillie Bowen, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Group photo, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8; Photograph is rolled and in a very fragile state. Conservation will be needed to fully view this photograph (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Group photo, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8; Photograph is rolled and in a very fragile state. Conservation will be needed to fully view this photograph (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Music class, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Students on roof of campus building, undated; Series 2 Subseries 8 (Box 39, Folder 11)
- Scrapbook pages, 1890-1968; 1901-1946; Series 3
  This series contains loose pages from student scrapbooks, as well as two complete scrapbooks in their original housing. These scrapbooks contain student photos, event programs, event descriptions composed by students, and more. Created by students for student use, these materials provide an intimate look at college life during the early past of the twentieth century.
  - Scrapbook ca. 1890-1920, possibly owned by Alma Schmidt c. 1914, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook Page - Students 1901-1903, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook Pages 1905-1906, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photos from Scrapbook of Dorothy Menefee Buxton, Class of 1914, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook Pages 1927-1929, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook page with Nancy Lee and classmates, 1928-1929; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clipping - Class Photo 1946, Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 1946-1952 (Oversized), Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Class of 1966 Scrapbook (Oversized), Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Cissy Wilson Scrapbook, 1968; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Administrative materials, 1916-1997; 1978-1997; Series 4
  Organized Chronologically
  This series contains faculty handbooks, correspondence, curriculum materials, factbooks, and other materials of administrative origin. Of particular interest are materials produced by Dr. Elmer Louis Kayser as part of a commencement speech given for Mount Vernon College, as well as materials produced by Mount Vernon historians chronicling the college's history. Materials date from the 1910's up to the 1990's.
  - M Street Collection - Certificates of Incorporation, 1916; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Elmer Louis Kayser - MVC Board of Trustees, 1939-1975; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Marjorie Post (Davies) to Mr. Lloyd - Fundraising, 1946; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Mount Vernon Junior College Faculty Handbooks 1961-1962, Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary and College Chronologies, 1978; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Walter Beach - MVC Archives Collecting Plans, 1978; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Victoria Schuck to M. M. Murphy, 1979; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Mount Vernon College Factbook 1986, Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Reaccreditation Self-Study Committee 1986, Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Division of Liberal Studies Notebook - Manuals [1/4], 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Division of Liberal Studies Notebook - Infosheets, Resumes, Schedule and Contracts [2/4], 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Division of Liberal Studies Notebook - Calendar, Orientation, Purchase Orders [3/4], 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Division of Liberal Studies Notebook - General Information & Monthly Budget [4/4], 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Reaccreditation Self-Study Committee 1996 [1/2], Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Reaccreditation Self-Study Committee 1996 [2/2], Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Core 101 Curriculum Books [1/2], 1997; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Core 101 Curriculum Books [2/2], 1997; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - MVC Library Bookplate, Undated; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Brochures, 1950-1980; 1965-1967; Series 5
  This series features brochures and lookbooks for prospective Mount Vernon students, featuring photographs of the campus and student life. Materials date from the 1950's to the 1980's.
  - Campus Brochures and Lookbooks ca. 1950's - 1980's, 1950-1980; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Washington Summer Program in American Politics and Government, 1965; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Mount Vernon Junior College Student Handbook 1967-1968, Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Event programs, 1925-2000; 1950-1988; Series 6
  This series contains event programs and calendars which describe special events at Mount Vernon ranging from theater productions, to commencements, to alumni events. Materials date between the mid 1920's to the 1990's, with the bulk of the material dating to the mid-twentieth century.
  - Calendar of Reverent Memory 1925, Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Events, 1928-1981; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Founder's Day and Centennial Celebrations, 1947-1975; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Theater Productions, 1949-1971; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Commencement Programs, 1950-1999; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Class Night 1959, Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Antique Show, 1967; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Chapel and Creed, 1967; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Musical/Concerts, 1977-1979; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - College President Inaugurations and Farewells, 1977-1992; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - MVC Poetry Festival, 1982; Series 6 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Fashion Show of Eleven Decades, 1985; Series 6 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Agnes DeLano Special Collections Room Dedication, 1988; Series 6 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Tennis Classic Programs, 1988-1995; Series 6 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Celebration of Prestigious African American Women, 1996; Series 6 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Educating Women for Leadership Seminar, 2000; Series 6 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Student and alumni publications, 1944-1997; Series 7
  This series contains yearbooks, newsletters, student government reports, and literature magazines produced for both student and alumni consumption. The bulk of the material dates to between the 1960's and 1980's.
  - Vignette 1944, Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Alumnae Bulletin, 1947-1987; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Carousel, 1961-1963; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Student Council/Gov't Association, 1977; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Asylum Magazine, 1978-1979; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - The New Merriweather Post, 1991; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Student's Voice, 1997; Series 7 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Artifacts, 1875-1995; 1950-1975; Series 8
  Organized ad hoc in a single box (Box 21), with overflow of Slide Viewer to Box 22.
  This series contains artifacts relating to Mount Vernon College, including small commerative plaques for alumni, MVC-themed paraphenalia, letter which hung in frames in various Mount Vernon buildings, and other various items. The material dates from 1875 to 1995.
  - Copy of Nancy Elizabeth Jenkin's Bachelor of Arts Degree, 1875; Series 8 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Class Year Silver Plaques, 1877-1925; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Compilation of letters from and photograph of John Wittier to Adelie Perry Burr, 1889; Series 8 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Compilation of letters from and photograph of Oliver Holmes to Adelie Perry Burr, 1889; Series 8 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Plaques of Commemoration, 1925; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Centenery medal featuring Elizabeth J. Somers, 1937; Series 8 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Plaque in Memory of Mary Lindsay, ca. 1950's; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ann Goldsmith's varsity letters (2), 1958-1959; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - Ann Goldsmith's invitations to the United States Naval Academy dance, 1958-1962; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - Faculty comments on Ann Goldsmith's studies, 1959 January; Series 8 (Box 37, Folder 64)
  - National Junior Honor Society of Secondary Schools Charter, 1965-1967; Series 8 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Frankie Welch MVC Scarf, ca. 1970's; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Framed Letter from Gerald Ford, 1975; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Framed Letter from Walter E. Washington, 1975; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Chi Society, 1980; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Non-profit Certification for D.C., 1994; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Certificate to Mount Vernon College Book and Print Shop - "Member National Association of College Stores", 1994-1995; Series 8 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Engraved Gavel of the Chairman of the Board of Trustees, Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Item 12)
  - Framed historical note about the mantel in Post Hall, undated; Series 8 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Gavel, Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Item 13)
  - MVC Diploma Holder, Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - MVC Photo Book (Empty), Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - MVC Poker Chip and Press on Regardless Button, Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - School Bell, Undated; Series 8 (Box 21, Item 11)
  - Slide Viewer and Glass Slides in Case, Undated; Series 8 (Box 22, Item 1)
  - Three rings (one with initials "PGS"), undated; Series 8 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Watercolor miniature painting of the Duc de Choiseul, undated; Series 8 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Watercolor miniature painting of the Duchess de Choiseul, undated; Series 8 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- Oversized photographs and plaques, 1875-1986; 1922-1986; Series 9
  Organized by subject into 5 boxes: Box 22 contains Class Photos, Box 23 contains Campus Photos, Box 24 contains theater and student life photo, and Boxes 25 and 26 contain plaques.
  This series contains photographs, architectural blueprints, and plaques which need to be stored separately due to their large size. Of particular interest are a comprehensive set of photographs from a 1962 production of Peter Pan, and blueprints to the Mount Vernon College Library. The material dates from 1911 to 1986.
  - Photograph: Group of MVS students amd faculty (on display mount), Circa late 1800s; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Cover of commencement program for first graduating class (on display mount), 1878 June 7; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Cover of "Nautilus" (on display mount), 1886-1887; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Secretary Addie P. Burr to Mattie Lemon (on display mount), 1887 May 7; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Invitation from the Nautilus Club (on display mount), 1888 May 25; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - MVS calendar and expenses (on display mount), 1904-1905; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Mount Vernon Seminary Glee Club of 1911-1912, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - MVS "Special Class" of 1911-1912, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Wood block image of Alexander Hamilton done by T. Cole, 1922; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - MVC student's handbook (pages on display mounts), 1923-1924; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Photograph: Two alums from the Class of 1879 at the Golden Jubilee (on display mount), 1925; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Postcards of Washington D.C. Landmarks, 1927; Series 9 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Somers 1937 Centenary Copper Plaque, Series 9 (Box 26, Item 2)
  - 1875-1937 MVC Copper Sign, Series 9 (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Photograph: Students gathered for the concert (on display mount), Circa 1940s; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Drawings by Wesley Bessell for the Foxhall Road Campus, 1945; Series 9 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Political cartoon drawn by Herblock, 1948; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - "Non opus est erbis: credite rebus" Wooden Plaque, 1950; Series 9 (Box 25, Item 3)
  - Photograph: Social gathering of students (on display mount), Circa 1950s; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Photograph: Social gathering of students (on display mount), Circa 1950s-1960s; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Framed Photo of Students on National Mall, ca. 1960's; Series 9 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Peter Pan Production, 1962; Series 9 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Class Photo Plaque 1973, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Mount Vernon College Class of 1973, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Class Photo Plaque ca. 1980's, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Undetermined Building ca. 1980's, Series 9 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Class Photo Plaque 1981, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Mt. Vernon Fall Tennis 1981, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Mt. Vernon Volleyball 1981, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Library Architectural Sketches 1985, Series 9 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Class Photo 1986, Series 9 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - MVC Library Blueprints, 1986; Series 9 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Alpha Chi Honor Society Plaque, Undated; Series 9 (Box 25, Item 1)
  - Photograph: Elizabeth J. Somers (on display mount), undated; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Photograph: Interior of campus chapel (on display mount), undated; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Photograph: Man and woman outside chapel (on display mount), undated; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Photograph by Frances Haynes Hilgartner - "Fishing on the Susquehanna", undated; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Photograph by Frances Haynes Hilgartner - "Strasbourg, France (View II)", undated; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Undetermined Society Plaque - Torch and Omega, Undated; Series 9 (Box 25, Item 2)